ONUR OVALI

Summary

Product manager based in Istanbul w/ 10 years of product development experience (5 years - software development & 5 years - product management), all in online products. CS graduate with an MBA. Interested in digital product management based on customer insights (data analysis and customer interviews) in agile teams/companies.

Employment

Head of Product Management

Kariyer.net

May 2019 - Present

Managed the product team of 8 PMs, responsible for Kariyer.net Job Board (B2C), Kariyer.net Applicant Tracking System (B2B) and İşin Olsun (blue collar job board & ATS) and micro products like iskolig.com & HRVenue.com.

- Managed the **relationships** with internal & external **shareholders** allowing the POs to focus on their tasks.
- Improved each POs skills and knowledge w/ continous educations, performance management practices and 1-1 meetings, developed autonomous and confident product managers who can make strategical decisions.
- High-valued customers' big problem was **irrelavant candidates**. Designed new products/services like Smart Job Ads (suggesting best-fitting candidates w/out application), Express Search (detailed search functionality), Assessment Tests Marketplace (local test providers sell their tests inside ATS). These new modules decreased the number of complaints and also increased non-essential products' **revenue by 40%**.
- Changed the UX flow of the posting a job ad process and increased job ad details by 30%
- Designed an **open API** to add 4 new modules (Assessment Marketplace, Video Interviews, KVKK (GDPR) & Survey Modules) with the same UX & data flow and **saved on development** source (1 int. instead of 15).
- Re-designed company profiles on the job-board w/ the CMS on the ATS. The company profiles' traffic tripled.
- Designed a **personalized** Profile page, offering relevant content for logged in candidates. Resulted in 40% increase on the ratio of updating resume and 30% increase on the users who view a job ad page after login.
- Lead the data science team on converting all static and rule-based processes into data-driven models.

Product & Marketing Manager

Turna.com

Dec 2017 - Apr 2019

Managed product analytics and performance marketing for Turna.com - an e-commerce platform for flight tickets.

- Created **automated funnel reports** for each channel (apps & web), used for **conversion rate optimization**. Decreased payment errors by 15% and increased total **conversion rate by 30%**.
- Created automated ROI & P&L reports for campaigns, optimized budget allocations. Improved ROI by 90%.
- Created **customer lifetime value** (LTV) report, interviewed top 50 customers. Discovered new segments with **insights gained**. Designed new campaigns and **attracted new customers with high LTV**.
- Defined **behavioral segments** and run email marketing campaigns. Achived better results (**higher conversion rates** and **lower CPAs**) than paid campaigns. Thus, designed an **inbound marketing automation project** which became an R&D project supported by government due to its improvement models with **Machine Learning**.

Technical Product Manager

Biletbank.com

Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

Led the microservices transformation project for B2B online travel agency (SaaS product).

- Software was in **monolithic** architecture. Started the microservices transformation project. Created the **architecture of all services' interfaces** and the **database designs**.
- Analyzed business requirements, created user stories, designed new data structures and processes.
- Defined the MVP, planned the project, created & prioritized tasks and managed the backlog.
- By implementing branching and automatic deployment; solved productivity problems of development team.
- Presented **Scrum & Agile** to the team, convinced using them and **increased efficiency**. Managed development & synch. of multiple teams and products with **Lean Startup** methodology; met deadlines and project targets.

Software Developer / Analyst

T. İs Bankası A.Ş.

Nov 2010 - Aug 2015

Full-stack developer for Isbank Internet Branch - one of the biggest private banks in Turkey.

• Developed web services for 2 factor authentication methods including OTP generators and iOS Touch ID.

- Performed **bug tracking** for internet branch, coordinating work of multiple teams with an SLA for open bugs.
- Supported IT Security team with Intrusion Detection Tests, after passing ISACA CISA June 2012 exam.

Education

MBA

Koç University, Istanbul

Sep 2015 - Dec 2017

- General MBA Program with a focus on innovation management, entrepreneurship & marketing.
- International attendance:

§ IE Business School, Madrid, Spain: Sales & Marketing (Erasmus Program)	Aug-Dec 2017
§ Hitotsubashi ICS, Tokyo, Japan: Innovation X Globalisation: Japan Style	Mar 2017
§ IE Business School, Madrid, Spain: High Tech Entrepreneurship (online course)	Jan-Mar 2017
§ Yale SOM, New Haven, USA: Behavioral Economis, Marketing & Finance	Oct 2016

BSc in Computer Engineering

METU, Ankara

Sep 2005 - Jul 2010

• Bachelor's Degree on Computer Science Program with a focus on algorithms, OOP & Al.

Certifications

 Deeply Practical Project Management issued by Udemy. Credential ID: UC-LCHJ8SAA 	Sep 2018
 Advanced Google Analytics Certificate issued by GA Academy. Credential ID: 234472174 	Aug 2018
• ISACA CISA (Certified Information System Auditor). Exam passed, certification not received.	Jun 2012

Skills, Knowledge & Tools

Product Management

- Experience on product strategy, market analysis, growth, benchmarking, product analytics & user interviews.
- Worked on many sides of product development life cycle in different agile (scrum) teams/companies.
- Experienced on user stories, flow diagrams w/ detailed case analysis; allowing simple & clear briefs for design (UX/UI professionals) & development teams.
- Prioritization, backlog & shareholder relations management is an everyday task.
- Hands-on experience on project mng. tools: Jira, Confluence, SmartSheet, Trello, Basecamp, Asana & others.

Analytics & Digital Marketing

- Advanced knowledge on analytics tools **Google Analytics**, **Datastudio**, **GTM**, **Firebase** & Kochava.
- Advanced on managing **performance campaigns**: segmentation, reporting & optimization.
- Hands on reporting experience on Google Ads, FB Business Mng & Criteo.
- Advanced knowledge on office programs (Excel, Powerpoint, etc.).

Computer Science

- Deep knowledge on **SQL** with professional experience on **T-SQL** & **Microsoft SQL Server**.
- Advanced knowledge on CS basics: Algorithms, Data Structures, Database & web services design.
- Professional coding experience on **Python** & **C#**, basic knowledge on Java, C++.
- Best practices of RDBMS & NoSQL (Couchbase, MongoDB) usage.
- Basic knowledge on cloud computing on AWS & cost optimization.

Languages

Native in Turkish, fluent in English, intermediate in Spanish.

written in LATEX